# John Marc Casquio

Quirino Avenue, Pandacan, Manila 109469299646 Casquiojohnmarc@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/j in ohn-marc-casquio-8ab968157

Versatile and experienced professional with Web Programmer, Project Management, QA Analyst/Tester, and Database Management expertise. I have successfully delivered and enhanced numerous projects from concept to launch. My experiences in various technologies and collaborating with various nationalities, tools, and problem-solving skills allow me to adapt to new challenges and provide quality results. An employee that can work independently but also a team player that can collaborate with cross functional team.

## **Experience**

#### November 2023 - November 2024

#### Web Programmer | Pacific Sea BPO Services, Inc. | Makati, Philippines

Managed internal websites developed with Codelgniter, PHP, HTML, CSS, jQuery, and various plugins, overseeing the creation of new features and the enhancement of existing functionality. Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams, including QA, front-end developers, UI/UX designers, web designers, and project managers, to ensure the delivery of high-quality solutions. Handled some front-end development tasks and database management. Additionally, developed several mini-projects using Laravel, jQuery, and Bootstrap.

#### February 2022 – March 2023

#### Jr Fullstack Web Developer | WeDo BPO Services, Inc | Ortigas, Philippines

Successfully developed four key projects, including two company websites, a payroll system, a hotel management system, and a point-of-sale system, utilizing technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Axios, PHP, Laravel, SQL, and WordPress. Managed both company and client databases, ensuring smooth data operations. Maintained daily communication with clients and prepared weekly reports for Monday stakeholders meetings. Documented system workflows and processes, and handled website management through GoDaddy and cPanel.

#### **Freelance Works**

#### Project Manager | Plumnetworks | Canada

Successfully managed 13 client projects from diverse nationalities, utilizing various technologies including Laravel, Codelgniter, PHP, WordPress, Shopify, WIX, React, and more, overseeing each project from initiation to completion. Of these, 9 were developed from scratch, while the remainder were transitioned from previous project managers, and deployed 8 projects before contract deadlines. Actively monitored project progress to ensure alignment with goals and objectives, and maintained daily communication with stakeholders, including team members, clients, and management, to ensure smooth project execution.

#### QA Analyst Level 1 Support | Genius Education | Brooklyn, NY

Performed daily testing to identify and resolve bugs and issues reported by clients and users. Executed test cases, documented defects, and verified the implementation of fixes. Provided technical support to both users and clients, ensuring timely resolutions. Utilized regression, functional, manual, and automated testing methods to thoroughly address and document all encountered bugs.

January 2021 – January 2022

#### UI/UX | 1Travel | United Kingdom

Created mock-ups and templates, and deployed custom CSS classes for the easy usage of the front-end team. Conducted user research and surveys to further improve website designs. Collaborated with cross-functional teams and stakeholders to ensure that the design met the client's standards.

## **Education**

June 2015 - April 202 BS Information Technology Forbes College Legazpi

### Skills

PHP, Laravel, Codeigniter Javascript, JQuery, AJAX, Axios HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind Database Management UI/UX Management QA (Manual and Automated Testing)
ZAP Penetration Testing
Project Management
Troubleshooting

## **Tools**

Microsoft Office Suites Redmine
Google Suites AWS Wickr Pro

Figma Slack Adobe XD Zoom Canva Skype Draw.io Docker **Adobe Suites** XAMPP Zendesk **VSCode** Jira Github Notion Gitlab